(
"ai_sub_version": "3.6.0",
"generated_at": "2026-10-08T02:37:40.421879",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": false,
"max_retries_exceeded": true,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"service_tier": null,
"service_tier_subtitles": null,
"service_tier_lyrics": null,
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
火の用心じゃ～！
Beware of fire~!
あらあら～？ めらめら～？ 熱千めら～！
Ara-ara~? Mera-mera~? Atsuchimera~!
ホロライブ アソビ★まわり隊 ご利益担当の火消し屋サラマンダー 熱千めらなのじゃ！
I'm Atsuchimera, the blessing-bringing firefighter salamander of hololive's Asobi Mawaritai!
みなさん！ はじめまして！！
Hello everyone! Nice to meet you!!
2026年9月24日に ホロライブからデビューした ピカピカの新人VTuberなのじゃ～！
I'm a shiny new VTuber who debuted from hololive on September 24, 2026~!
今日は わしの自己紹介動画を 撮っていこうと思うのじゃ！
Today, I'm going to record my self-introduction video!
「どんな子かな～？」とか気になってたり 「人間じゃないの？」「なんで髪の毛燃えてるの？」とか 「ホロライブのオーディションを受けた時の話」とかもしようかなって思ってるので
I'm planning to talk about things like "What kind of girl is she?", "Isn't she human?", "Why is her hair on fire?", and my experience auditioning for hololive!
この動画を見て わしのこと いっぱい知ってくれたら 嬉しいのじゃ！
So I'd be really happy if you could get to know me well through this video!
ということで 動画スタート！！
With that said, let's start the video!!
名前は 熱千めら！ 「ねっせん」じゃないのじゃ！ 「あちち」って読むのじゃ！
My name is Atsuchimera! It's not read "Nessen"! It's read "Atsuchi"!
「千度の熱」と書いて 「熱千（あちち）」 良い名前なのじゃ！
Written as "Heat of a thousand degrees", it's "Atsuchi"! It's a great name!
そして「めら」 メメラメラの「めら」なのじゃ！ 火が燃えてる時の オノマトペ？ 擬音？ みたいのなやつなのじゃ！
And "Mera" comes from "mera-mera" (flaming)! It's like an onomatopoeia or sound effect for fire burning!
漢字がちょっと分かりづらいのと あと辞書で一発で出てこないので
Since the kanji is a bit confusing and doesn't pop up right away in dictionaries...
めら組のお主らは 熱千（あちち）を辞書登録して いつでも熱千（あちち）を呼び出せるようにするのじゃ！
Everyone in Mera-gumi, please add "Atsuchi" (熱千) to your dictionary so you can type it anytime!
そして お主らが気になってるであろう種族！ わしは サラマンダーなのじゃ！
And now, the species you're probably curious about! I am a salamander!
見て このツノ ツノ！ あと 尻尾なのじゃ～！ どうかのぉ？ 可愛いかのぉ？
Look at these horns! Horns! And my tail~! How is it? Cute, right?
サラマンダーとは 火を司る精霊らしいのじゃ！
A salamander is said to be a spirit that governs fire!
わしの髪の毛からもね こうやって炎が出とおるじゃろ
That's why flames are coming out of my hair like this, right?
これは 体内の熱を どこかから出さないと わしが火を吹いちゃって 周りを火だらけにしちゃう
If I don't release internal heat, I'll breathe fire and set everything around me ablaze.
髪から火を出すことで、火を暴発しないようにしている。
Releasing fire from my hair prevents accidental outbursts.
わしてきには 正直人間と変わらんくね？ と思ってるところがあって
Honestly, to me, I feel like I'm not that different from a human.
火に強いとは言いつつも 火傷はするのじゃ
Even though I'm strong against fire, I still get burned.
手とか指とかは火傷しないが、粘膜は火傷する。
My hands and fingers don't burn, but my mucous membranes do.
それこそベロとか あったかいココアとか飲む時は ベロ火傷しちゃう
Especially my tongue. When I drink warm cocoa, I burn my tongue.
あと 炎属性なんじゃが 夏はめちゃくちゃ暑いのじゃ！
Also, even though I'm fire-elemental, summer is super hot!
本当にサラマンダー？ 湿度とかもあるからな？ ヤバいから 熱中症になる サラマンダーなのに！
Are you really a salamander? Maybe because of humidity, it's so bad I get heatstroke, even as a salamander!
本当にサラマンダー？（2回目） 熱中症とか火傷とか そういうのならないようにすればいいのにな
Are you really a salamander? (2nd time) I wish I were immune to heatstroke and burns.
わしは火を吹いたりできるのじゃ！
Also, I can breathe fire!
火を吹くところはね わしが火を吹くかっこいい姿を見たければ 情報解禁時のPVを見るのじゃ！
If you want to see me looking cool breathing fire, watch the reveal PV!
わしの年齢は 415歳！ 長生きなのじゃ～
My age is 415 years old! I'm long-lived~
生年月日と言うと 1611年4月16日生まれなのじゃ
Speaking of date of birth, I was born on April 16, 1611.
何年何月何日とか言ったんじゃが 厳密には覚えてなくて 大体 江戸時代だった気がするのじゃ～
I gave a specific date, but strictly speaking, I don't really remember—roughly Edo period~
あとわしは良い子じゃから 415（よいこ）歳ってことにしようと思って
Also, since I'm a good child (yoi-ko), I decided to make my age 415 (yoi-ko) years old!
割適当？ 良い子（415）だから、年齢は415歳ってことになった。生年月日は逆算で決めた。
Quite random? Since I'm a good child (415), my age became 415. The birthdate was calculated backwards.
全部うろ覚えなのじゃ そんな何百年も前のことを 覚えてる訳ないのじゃ！
My memory is vague! There's no way I'd remember something from hundreds of years ago!
逆ギレもしよう。 大体400歳くらいだと思っておいてくれれば良いと思うのじゃ。
Getting defensive too. Just think of me as roughly 400 years old!
そして400年前 生まれたての頃 何をしていたかと言うと 火消しという職業をしていたのじゃ！
And 400 years ago, when I was freshly born, I worked as a firefighter!
火消しってのは現代で言うところの 消防団みたいな 文字通り火事を消すのじゃ
Firefighting is like modern-day fire brigades, literally putting out fires.
わしはサラマンダーじゃから ある程度 火には強くて 炎に強いサラマンダーを活かし 火消しとして火事の現場に駆けつけて消火活動をしていた。
Since I'm fire-resistant, I rushed to fire scenes as a firefighter to extinguish flames.
そしてわしは 纏持（まtoi-mochi）というものを やっていたのじゃ！
And I was working as a standard-bearer (matoi-mochi)!
火消しっていう 火を消す人たちがいるじゃろ？
There are people who extinguish fires, right?
纏持として消火活動の指揮をする 役職を担当していた。
As a standard-bearer, I was in charge of directing firefighting operations.
当然 人間の寿命よりも わしの寿命の方が長いから 仲良かった人間たちが みんななくなっちゃって しばらく1人でいるか～と思って その後は山に籠ってたのじゃ 200年くらい
Naturally, humans live shorter lives, so after my human friends passed away, I retreated into the mountains for ~200 years.
山に籠ってる間にしていたこと 寝て 起きて 食べて 寝てたのじゃ 食っちゃ寝サラマンダー？ ずっと寝て起きて食べて寝ての生活をしてたのじゃ
What I did in the mountains: slept, woke up, ate, and slept. A lazy eat-and-sleep salamander lifestyle!
山から降りて 人間と一緒に暮らし始めてから 今まで20年くらい 人間と共に生活をしてきたのじゃ 約200年間、山に籠り食っちゃ寝サラマンダーとして過ごしていた。山から降り、人間と暮らし始めてからは約20年。
After coming down, I've lived with humans for ~20 years. 200 years in mountains, 20 years with humans.
なんで わしが人間と暮らし始めたか？ という話なんじゃが わしが山で生活していた時にの 山にスマホが捨ててあったんじゃよ 「スマホおもれ～！」と思って
Why did I start living with humans? When living in the mountains, I found a discarded smartphone!
触ってたら わしは匿名掲示板を発見したんじゃよ 匿名掲示板で 「これ会話できるのでは～！」と思って そこに書き込みとかをしてたんじゃよ 人間と話せるの嬉しくて
I discovered an anonymous board, thought "I can chat here!", and posted because I was happy to talk with humans.
Error processing subtitles for this segment.
わし SAKKAC CRAFT っていうアルバムがガチで大好きなのじゃ
I really, truly love the album called SAKKAC CRAFT.
オーディションの書類審査の時に「あなたの好きなものについて語ってください」みたいな質問があって
During my audition screening, there was a question asking to talk about things I like.
そこでわしが書いた文章を「今日はそのまま貼って良いよ」って言われたから貼っちゃうのじゃ
I was told I could show what I wrote back then today, so I'm putting it up!
さっき言ったツミキさんが書いた ボカロ曲じゃないんじゃけど「トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ」っていう曲がめちゃくちゃ好きで その曲について書いてみたのじゃ
I wrote about "Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous", a non-Vocaloid song by Tsumiki that I absolutely love!
わしのオーディションの時に送った文章を見て欲しいのじゃ
I'd like you to see the application letter I submitted for my audition.
ドーン！こういう書類はですね ですます口調で喋ってるのじゃ
Ta-da! On documents like this, I actually wrote using polite language.
さすがにここでタメ語ってやつで喋ると 常識が無い奴って思われるからの
Because if I used casual talk, they'd think I lack common sense!
のじゃ略でお送りさせていただいておりますが こんな感じで書いて送ったのじゃ
So I wrote it politely, omitting "no-ja"—this is what I sent!
これくらいわしはボカロ曲 そしてボカロPさんが作曲した曲が大なのじゃ！
That's how much I love Vocaloid songs, and songs composed by Vocaloid producers!
そして好きなもの③！なろう系！なろう系めっちゃ好きなのじゃ！
Next, Thing I Like #3! "Narou" web light novels! I love Narou stories so much!
味方が誰も死なない あんまり苦しいハラハラが無いというか
Allies never die, and there aren't many painful or stressful suspenseful moments.
ずっと気持ち良く勝ち続けるみたいな 成り上がりって感じじゃから 見ててずっと気持ちいいのじゃ
It's all about comfortable winning streaks and rising up, so it feels great to read!
不安な気持ちにならない内容が多いから 元気ない時とかに「今日は元気ないから...」
Most of them don't make you feel anxious, so on days when I feel down...
「お布団で1日ぐーたらしていようかな」って日とかに ずっとなろう系ばっかり読んでいるのじゃ
...and think, "I'll just laze in bed all day," I just read Narou web novels nonstop!
なろう系以外にも漫画自体が好きで 少年ジャンプの作品とかも好きなのじゃ
Besides Narou, I generally love manga, including Shonen Jump titles.
アニメとか漫画はね わしこの辺が好きなのじゃ
When it comes to anime and manga, these are the ones I love.
怖いもの発表しようかな！怖いもの① サーモン！サーモンって怖くないですか？
Now, let's reveal things I'm afraid of! Fear #1: Salmon! Isn't salmon scary?
なんかわし ちっちゃい頃はね 焼き鮭を結構食べてたんじゃよ で焼き鮭大好きで
When I was little, I ate a lot of grilled salmon. I loved grilled salmon!
初めて回転寿司に行った時に わしは英語をちょっと分かってたから「サーモン」って文字を見て「これは鮭じゃ」と思って
The first time I went to conveyor belt sushi, I knew a bit of English, so seeing "Salmon", I thought, "Ah, this is salmon!"
鮭大好きじゃから この回転寿司でもサーモンとやらを食べてみようではないかと思って お皿を取るじゃないですか
Since I loved grilled salmon, I thought, "Let me try this salmon stuff!" and took a plate.
焼き鮭だと思ってサーモンを食べるじゃないですか
Expecting grilled salmon, I ate the raw salmon sushi, right?
頭がバグって「なんじゃ」と思って「わしが今まで食べてたあの魚は何処へ」と思って！そこからずっと怖いのじゃ
My brain glitched! I was like, "What is this?! Where's the fish I usually eat?!" Ever since, I've been terrified!
何が起きてるか分かんなくて「これが来る！」と思って食べてみたら全然違う
I didn't understand what happened. I expected one thing, but it tasted entirely different!
しかもしかも なんか濡れてた！しっとりしてる！
Plus, it felt raw and moist! So smooth!
しばらくはそこからサーモンが食べれなかったのじゃ 怖すぎて
For a long time after that, I couldn't eat salmon because it was too scary.
最初から別物だと思って食べれば怖くないと思って そっからは普通に食べれるのじゃ
Once I convinced myself it's a completely different food, I wasn't scared anymore, so now I can eat it normally.
今では毎回サーモンを食べるぐらい好きだが...好きなんじゃよ！でも 好きじゃけど怖くて「なんじゃ！？」と思いながらいつも食べてるのじゃ
Now I like it enough to order it every time, but while eating I'm still internally screaming, "What is this?!"
怖いもの其の二！トースター！これはもう説明不要な気がするのじゃ
Fear #2: Toasters! I feel like this doesn't even need an explanation.
トースターって怖くない？わしパン好きなんじゃが トースターって急に出てきて怖い！「はわわ」ってなるのじゃ
Aren't toasters terrifying? I love bread, but toasters pop up so suddenly! It panics me!
「焼き上がりました！ヌルヌル～」って出てきてくれたら「焼き上がったな～」って思うんじゃが ポンッて出てくるから「ひゃあ！」ってなるのじゃ
If it slowly slid out saying "It's toasted!", I'd be fine, but it suddenly pops up, making me gasp!
あれやめて欲しい びっくりさせるのズルいなんのじゃ
I wish it wouldn't do that. Jump scares are unfair!
怖いもの丸三！炎上なんのじゃ！炎上ガチで怖いのじゃ...やめて欲しいのじゃ...
Fear #3: Getting canceled online! Online flame wars are genuinely terrifying... I want no part in them...
人生で初めて触ったインターネットで叩かれを経験してるから めっちゃ過剰に恐れている...気がするのじゃ
Since I got heavily criticized the very first time I touched the internet, I think I'm excessively paranoid about it...
初手で山特定されてますからね わしら
Because right off the bat, people identified the exact mountain I lived on!
「お前住んでる山ここだろ」言われてますからね ガチ怖かったよアレ 外出れんよ
They said, "This is the mountain you live on, right?" That was insanely terrifying! I couldn't go outside!
インターネットってルールとか空気感とかあるじゃろ？あれ初見殺しだと思うのじゃ わし
The internet has all these unwritten rules and tacit culture, right? I think it's a trap for beginners!
アクセスする難易度って低いじゃろ？見るのも楽しく見れるじゃろ？書き込むのも簡単じゃろ？初めてインターネット触ったのに書き込めたよ？書き込めたのに駄目だった！
Accessing it is easy, browsing is fun, and posting is simple. I posted on my first day online, but it went horribly wrong!
もっとルールとか書いて欲しいよね！「◯◯はこうしてください！」「◯◯はしちゃいけません！」みたいなの全部書いて欲しいのじゃ！だからすっごい気付けようと思うのじゃ
I wish they had explicit rules written out! Like "Do this" or "Don't do that"! That's why I try to be extra careful now.
わしの夢！わしの夢は人間にお返しをする事なんのじゃ
My dream! My dream is to repay my debt of gratitude to humans!
人間として20年間生きてきて 仲間に入れてもらえたのがめちゃくちゃ嬉しかったのじゃ
Having lived as a human for 20 years and being accepted as one of you made me so happy.
200年ぐらいずっとひとりぼっちじゃったし ずっと寂しかったから 構ってもらえたのがすごく嬉しくて 人間好きなのじゃ
I was alone for about 200 years and always lonely, so being cared for made me so happy—I love humans!
わしもかつてのわしみたいに 今居場所がなくてひとりで寂しいって思ってる人間が もしかしたらいるかもしれないと思って わしはそんな人間の居場所になりたいのじゃ
Thinking there might be people like my past self—lonely with nowhere to belong—I want to become a safe haven for them.
次はわしが居場所になることによって 人間に恩を返していくという作戦なんのじゃ
My plan is to return the favor to humanity by being a place where they belong!
そしてインターネットでやっぱわしかつて痛い目に遭いましたから どんな人間にも優しい インターネット1年生でも初心者の方々でも入りやすい そんな配信や動画を作りたいのじゃ
And since I had a harsh experience online, I want to create streams and videos that are welcoming to everyone, even internet beginners.
あったかい居場所にしたいのじゃ！みんな協力してくれるかの？協力して欲しいのじゃ！
I want to make it a warm place to be! Will you all help me? Please help me out!
いかがでしたでしょうか？わしの自己紹介動画見て 熱干めらというサラマンダーがどんな子なのかちょっとは分かってくれたかの？これから配信とか動画とか見て もっと色んなわしのことを知っていって欲しいなとは思いつつ...
How was that? After watching my self-intro video, do you understand a bit more about what kind of salamander Nekkan Mera is? I hope you'll watch my streams and videos to learn even more about me...
この自己紹介動画さえ見てれば
As long as you've watched this self-introduction video,
熱千めら 9割ぐらい分かったと言っても
it wouldn't be an exaggeration to say
過言ではないぐらいな内容な気がする
that you've understood about 90% of Achichi Mera.
過言か？過言かあ
Is that an exaggeration? Maybe it is...
楽しんでもらえたなら 幸いなのじゃ！
If you enjoyed it, I'd be very happy!
最後に一言
And lastly, one final word...
わし 運命を信じてるのじゃ
I believe in destiny.
人生ってさ その時その時で出会うべき人がいるじゃないですか？
You know how in life, there are people you're meant to meet at certain times?
それがお主らにとっての その時出会うべきだった人が わしじゃったら良いな〜って思うんじゃよ
I really hope that I happen to be that person meant for you at that moment.
熱千めらと出会ってから すごい毎日楽しくなって 居場所になったよ
"Ever since I met Achichi Mera, every day has been so fun, and I found a place where I belong."
って思ってくれる人間が 1人でもいっぱいいたら わしはここに来た意味があったなって思うし
If as many people as possible feel that way, even one more person, I'll feel like coming here was worth it.
そうなるように これから お主にとっての温かい居場所に なることを願って 活動していきます！
So going forward, I'll keep streaming in hopes of becoming a warm, cozy place for you!
チャンネル登録・高評価・コメントなどで わしを応援して欲しいのじゃ〜！
I'd be so happy if you could support me through subscribing, liking, commenting, or any other way!
ボイスなどデビュー記念で様々なものが販売中なので チェックしてみて欲しいのじゃ〜！
Also, debut commemorative voice packs and various merch are on sale now, so please check them out if you're interested!
ということで 今日の動画はおしまいなのじゃ！
And with that, that's all for today's video!
また動画とか配信とか 色んなところで お主と会えると嬉しいのじゃ！
I'd be glad to see you again in videos, streams, or anywhere else!
これからよろしくね！
I look forward to spending time with you!
また次の何かでお会いしましょ〜
So then, let's meet again in the next video or stream!
ばいばいのじゃ〜！
Bye-bye!